# Mohammad Zaatari

Lebanon, Saida, Njasa Street 35

Phone Number: +961 / 81450826 | Email: mohamadalzaatari748@gmail.com | GitHub Profile: https://github.com/taha007860 |

LinkedIn Profile: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-al-zaatari-976347240/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-al-zaatari-976347240/</a>

"Know what you have to have what you want"

# **Personal Profile**

As a USAID scholar and computer scientist at the American University of Beirut, I have a passion for generating endless creative ideas and bringing them to life through deliberate and thoughtful implementation. I invest time in learning and researching to ensure the optimal execution of each project. With my technical skills in software/web development, and algorithm/data structure design, I'm equipped to turn these ideas into tangible results. I'm committed to delivering high quality work and continuously expanding my knowledge to improve and innovate. I'm excited to collaborate with others who share my enthusiasm for pushing the boundaries of what's possible.

# Education

### American University of Beirut (AUB)

Beirut, Lebanon

BS in Computer Science

Enrollment Date: Sept 2021 - Expected Graduation Date: May 2024

# Work Experience

**Amazon Web Services Mentorship program** in partnership with American University of Beirut (AUB)

Lebanon June 2023 - September 2023

Software Engineer

Built Fashion Recommendation System. Details listed in Projects section

#### Bennett&Ranville

Remote September 2023 - October 2023

**Software Researcher and Quality** 

Assurance

researched logging frameworks such as fluent bit and tested websites

## American University of Beirut

**Remote** September 2023 - November 2023 Assistant Business Analyst

**Skills:** Customer Relationship Management (CRM) · Microsoft Office · Microsoft Excel · Slate

CRM · Research · Data Analysis ·

Microsoft Word

## Integrated Digital Systems (IDS)

**Remote** November 2023 - Present Full-Stack Web Developer

Building a full-stack web application using ASP.NET Web API, C#, SQL Server Database and Frontend frameworks such as ReactJS. Currently working on this project.

# **Projects**

#### **Profile Card**

Crafted a visually appealing and responsive Profile Card

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS

Source Code and demo: https://github.com/taha007860/Profile-Card

### Hangman Game

Technical Skills: ReactJS, CSS

Source Code and demo: <a href="https://github.com/taha007860/hangman">https://github.com/taha007860/hangman</a>

# Pomodoro Clock

built a Pomodoro clock/timer that features smooth animations

Technical Skills: ReactJS, CSS

Source Code and demo:

https://github.com/taha007860/Pomodoro

### Regsitration Form

Complete Sign up, Login, and Logout User Authentication System **Technical Skills:** PHP, MySQL, phpMyAdmin, Apache

Server, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Source Code and demo:

https://github.com/taha007860/Registration-Form

### Weather App

Built a dynamic weather app that fetches and displays real-time weather information.

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Source Code and demo: https://github.com/taha007860/Weather-App

### **Email Administration**

Designed to simplify the process of creating email accounts for new hires

Technical Skills: Java

Source Code and demo: https://github.com/taha007860/Email-Administration

## **Home Page**

Built a sleek and responsive website homepage

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, SASS/SCSS

Source Code and demo: https://github.com/taha007860/Home-Page

Fashion Recommendation System

Built it using Deep Learning with a visually appealing web interface

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, Flask Python framework

Source Code and demo: https://github.com/OmarJltani/AmazonLook-Fashion-Recommendation-using-Deep-Learning

# **Achievements, Awards and Certificates**

Got USAID Scholarship at the American University of Beirut

Got Qatar Scholarship (Education Above All Program) at the American University of Beirut

Got 780/800 on Amideast Scholastic Assessment Test Math section (SAT Math)

Got 2nd place on Innovation Camp that was organized by INJAZ Lebanon

Got First place on the American University of Beirut Library Knowledge Competition

Got Badges, HTML/CSS/Microsoft PowerPoint skill badges with LinkedIn

# **Languages**

Arabic Native proficiency

English Professional